the code we've been given
will randomly assign either true or
false to the local variable boolean
and we can see that by outputting the
value of boolean
now this problem asks us to print the
string
i'm true if boolean is equal to true
and print the string i'm false if
boolean is equal to false
we can do this using an if statement
and we can provide boolean
as the condition to our if statement
if boolean is equal to true this first
branch of our if statement will be
executed
and we will output i'm true
otherwise if boolean is equal to false
the else branch of our if statement will
be executed
and we'll output the string i'm false
so let's run our code
and you can see our program is behaving
as expected
when the variable boolean evaluates as
true
we output the string i'm true and when
boolean references
false we output the string i'm false
so we're achieving the expected output
here using an if statement
however this problem asks us to write a
ternary
operator to achieve this output this
problem
is appropriate for a ternary operator
because there are only
two possible outcomes
the syntax of a ternary operator is seen
on line
four we provide a condition to our
ternary operator
and if that condition evaluates as true
the code on the left side of the colon
will be executed
if the condition evaluates as false
the code on the right side of the colon
will be executed
so let's think about how we can write a
ternary operator for this problem
again we can provide the local variable
boolean
as the condition to our ternary operator
boolean will evaluate to either true or
false
if boolean evaluates as true
we want to output the string i'm true
otherwise i'll put the string
i'm false
so let's run our code as it is now with
the ternary operator
and see if our program exhibits the same
behavior as it did when we used an if
statement
and it does
so a ternary operator is just another
type of conditional
that can be very useful when there are
only two
possible outcomes
you